Summary

5-6 years experience with data engineer and soft engineer. (Distributed Queue System, RMDB, NoSQL, TSDB, Web Crawling, RESTful API, ETL, Docker Swam, GKE(K8S), CICD, GCP, Airflow ...etc.)
1-2 years experience with data science. (Data Analysis, Machine Learning and Deep Learning)
Github project get 1,800 stars.

Work Experience

17 LIVE - Senior Data Engineer

May. 2021 - Now

- The main developer for refactor ETL. Creating a airflow project by **Cloud Composer** to transfer ETL tools from digdag to airflow and transfer ETL develop method from shell script to python. (More than 20 large pipelines.)
- Maintenance **BigQuery** more than 300 tables and more than 10 TB data.
- Create pipelines from backend team, multiple mysql and mongodb, and appsflyer to bigquery.
- Create Data Team's first **real-time ETL system via GKE, Pub/Sub and Memorystore** for sending push notifications to users. (Graceful Shutdown is also set.)
- Create a **good development culture**, including the introduction of CICD, dev-stage-master, unit tests and test coverage.
- Create document culture by **confluence**.
- Using Airflow unified scheduler job, like cloud function scheduler, bq scheduler, crontab, and ML model by R or Python ...etc.
- The finalists of **Break the Norm** awards on 2021-Q3 and 2021-Q4.
- Assist in **interview** more than 10 new data engineer.
- Mentor junior data engineers to be more effective individual contributors.

SinoPac Holdings - Software Engineer

Nov. 2019 - May. 2021

- Develop **python**, **C**# api for stock/option/future trading.
- Setup **CI/CD** with github actions and gitlab-ci to publish package and unit testing.https://meet.google.com/ryd-qpjx-oir
- Deploy a test system to simulate trading.
- Collecting distributed system log by elk, grafana and prometheus, 13 GB log data/day. https://www.overleaf.com/project/s
- System monitor of api latency, worker alive and user request count by telegram bot.
- Develop transaction-by-trade and odd lot trading API.

Openup Speaker (FinMind)

2019-12-01

Oct. 2018 - Oct. 2019

- **Tripresso Data Engineer**
 - Analysis travel data and build a machine learning model. Estimating increase 3% orders (revenue).
 - Maintain and develop an distributed queuing system for web crawling with 20 machines.
 - Optimize the ETL system reduced more than **50**% execution time.
 - Develop new product crawler let product volume increase 1.5%.
 - Making **BI charts** provide for other departments.

Publications

• Published a book related to data engineering. Python 大數據專案 X 工程 X 產品資料工程師的升級攻略. On major platforms, like tenlong, books, momoshop ...etc, the weekly sales are the highest TOP 1, and the monthly sales are the highest TOP 2.

1,800 Stars On Github. Sep. 2017 - Now

FinMind python project

- 3 team member.
- Create a payment flow by ECPay, and getting some order from user.
- More than 2,000 people registered.
- Open source of financial data, more than 50 dataset, more than 1 billion, 200GB.
- 10 million data per day.
- Deploy restful api, backend, web, crawler, rabbitmq, mysql, dolphindb, redis and loading balance by docker swarm and traefik.
- Transfer dataset from mysql to dolphindb, reduce 80% (150GB) data size.
- Using scheduler to automatic update data by airflow, rabbitmq and celery (8 cloud machines).
- Automated deployment web, backend and api by CI/CD.
- Using **vue**, **python and django** to develop web pages. (https://finmindtrade.com/).
- The API has more than **100,000** requests per day. Upper bound of api is **8,000/minute** request by ApacheBench.
- Design data pipeline for crawler, backend and analysis by airflow.

Bosch Production Line Performance (Kaggle) Grupo Bimbo Inventory Demand (Kaggle) Instacart Market Basket Analysis (Kaggle)

Post-competition analysis, top 6% rank. Post-competition analysis, top 8% rank. Final top 25% rank.

Education

National Dong Hwa University (GPA: 3.87)

Master of Science, Sep. 2017.

Major: Mathematics and Statistics.

Tamkang University

Bachelor of Science, Sep. 2015.

Major: Mathematics.